[ Audience Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Good morning.
&gt;&gt; 上午好
Perfect.
太棒了
Thank you very much.
非常感谢
So, welcome to today's session,
那么  欢迎参加今天的讲坛
Introduction to PDFKit on iOS.
对 iOS 版 PDFKit 的介绍
So much has changed in the last
过去这 12 个月里
twelve months, and we are super
我们做了许多改动
excited to show you all of those
我们特别激动地想让大家
changes and all of the big
看到所有的改动
improvements.
所有的重大改进
But before we begin, we should
但在开始前
introduce ourselves.
先介绍一下自己
My name is Jeremy Bridon.
我叫 Jeremy Bridon
I'm a Software Engineer here at
是 Apple 的软件工程师
Apple working on Core Graphics,
负责核心图形的工作
and --
然后
&gt;&gt; I'm Nicki Brower, also a
&gt;&gt; 我是 Nicki Brower
Software Engineer here at Apple.
也是 Apple 的软件工程师
&gt;&gt; Perfect.
&gt;&gt; 真棒
All right.
好
So, we've got a lot to talk
今天我们有
about today, but the very first
很多东西想讲
thing we're going to be talking
不过首先要讲的
about is the PDF file format
还是 PDF 文件格式
itself.
本身
We're then going to give a nice
然后我们会
little discussion over the
留些时间讨论一下
framework itself, followed by a
整个框架  接着
discussion on the document, page
讨论一下文档页面
and annotations model of that
和这个框架
framework.
用到的 annotation 模型
We're finally going to do a deep
最后我们会深入地
dive into annotations.
讲一下 annotation
So, annotations are something
那么  annotation 是我们
that we changed a lot this year
在今年改动最多的一块
based on feedback from
听取了像你们一样的
developers like you.
开发者的很多意见
So, we want to put some extra
所以在今年
effort into explaining all of
我们想要多花些心思
that this year.
好好解释一下这部分
Finally, for developers, old and
最后为了各位开发者们
new, we're going to do a
不论是老手还是新手
discussion on best practices,
我们会讨论一下最佳实践
things that we recommend you do.
也就是我们建议大家使用的做法
All right.
好
But first, let's talk about the
让我们先来聊一下
PDF file format spec being 1300
PDF 文件格式的规范说明
pages, a totally unacceptable
1300 页根本没法
number to try and understand how
让人看完和弄懂
the PDF file format works.
PDF 文件格式的原理
Right? You are app developers.
对吧大家都是应用开发者
We want you to create these
我们希望大家不必为
awesome applications without
细致入微的规范操心
worrying about the details of
照样能够开发出
the specification.
厉害的应用来
So, we've created an awesome
于是我们就设计了
framework that gives you the
一套出色的框架
power of PDF without you having
让大家不用读完那些规范
to read all those details.
就能发挥出 PDF 的强大力量
We read it, so you don't have
我们全读完了
to, all right.
所以大家就不用读了
So, why use PDFs in the first
那么首先
place?
为什么要用 PDF
Well, they're this kind of
这么说好了
universal business format.
PDF 是种通用的商务格式
They're universal and used in
它的使用很广泛
medical, financial, government,
医疗界  金融界  政府
and business applications, and
商务都有应用
they're done so because they've
PDF 如此普及是因为
got these wonderful features,
它确实有些很出色的特性
features like strong encryption
比如可靠的加密功能
or a variable permission model.
还有灵活多变的权限模型
So, some really, really nice
这些确实出色的地方
things directly applicable to
对各位开发者来说
you as developers, and then also
十分适用  也能满足
for business needs.
商务需要
What is also really cool about
PDF 还有一个
PDF is it's this interactive
很厉害的地方
model.
就是它的交互模型
Right? It's not just a static
对吧  它不只是一份
document that you print and you
静态文档打印出来
forget about it.
就被你忘在一边
No, it's this document that's
它的电子版文档
fully interactive in the digital
可以做到全面的交互
world, so I'm going to give you
所以我要向大家
the tools that allow you to
介绍几款工具让大家
interact with those documents on
能在我们的平台上
our platform.
做到与 PDF 文档的交互
So, of course, if you do
当然如果要做
interact with the document,
PDF 文档的交互
what's great is what you see in
最棒的效果就是
the digital world is what you
电子版是什么样
eventually see printed out in
印刷成实体版后
the physical world.
还是什么样
But it's this really complicated
但是当中涉及的规格
spec, and there's so many
实在太复杂还有
details to worry about.
很多细节要考虑
How can we kind of handle those
如今我们要如何
issues today?
处理这些问题呢
Nicki?
Nicki
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Okay.
&gt;&gt; 好的
So, we're excited about PDFs,
所以我们很看重 PDF
and we want to include them in
希望能把它
our application.
涵盖在我们的应用中
How do we do that?
那要怎么做呢
Well, we already have a solution
我们已经为大家
for you, and it's a lower level
做好了一套解决方案
solution, and it's using the
而且是套比较底层的方案
CoreGraphics PDF Framework.
用的是 CoreGraphics PDF 框架
This framework is great because
这套框架很了不起
it has a one-to-one drawing
因为它有一套基于 PDF 规格的
model with the PDF Spec. It
一对一绘制模型
allows you to read and write and
能让你读写和
modify your documents, and it
编辑文档它还有
has a PDF presser and a PDF
PDF 压制器
renderer, so you don't have to
PDF 渲染器
create one.
不用你自己创建
There are some limitations
不过它也有
though.
一些局限
Because it doesn't have any
它不含任何
AppKit primitives, that means
AppKit 基元
you don't get any live
这意味着你没法
interaction with the document.
与文档实时交互
That means no text selection, no
意味着不支持文本选取
highlighting search results, no
不支持搜索结果高亮
interaction with annotations,
不支持 annotation 交互
and it doesn't have any
也不提供任何
accessibility support.
可访问性支持
Well, this is where PDFKit comes
这时候就要靠
in.
PDFKit 了
So, PDFKit is based on the
所以 PDFKit 的构建基于
CoreGraphics Framework, but it
CoreGraphics 框架
also includes AppKit, so you get
但它同时整合了 AppKit
that live interaction with the
可以让你与文档
document.
进行实时互动
And now, as of this year, we are
然后在今年我们在针对
now on iOS; so not just AppKit
iOS 平台开发不光是 AppKit
but UIKit as well.
也包括 UIKit
So, it's now even easier to
所以现在你能更轻松地
open, modify, and draw your
打开修改绘制 PDF 文档
PDFs, but now you do get that
而且还能
interaction.
添加交互
You can select text; you can
你可以选取文本
interact with the annotations,
可以与 annotation 交互
and I want to point out that
我还想特别指出
this year we have made a great
在今年我们下了
effort to improve our
很大功夫来改进
accessibility support.
可访问性支持
So, by just using PDFKit, you
所以只要使用 PDFKit
get voiceover, text extraction,
就能做到文本朗读文本提取
being able to fill out forms,
能够填写表格
all for free.
全部是免费功能
All right.
好
Let's take a look at where
我们再来看一下
PDFKit is today.
PDFKit 现在的进展
On the Mac, you can see it's
在 Mac 上可以看到
used by Preview and Safari,
Preview 和 Safari 都有用到它
which are our main clients, but
这也是我们的主要客户
we're all over the platform as
但在各种平台上
well.
都有我们的身影
I just mentioned one, iOS, so
我刚才就提到了 iOS
you can see it's being used by
大家可以看到 iBooks
iBooks, Mail, and QuickLooks,
Mail 和 QuickLooks 都在用它
and hopefully we'll be able to
希望台下各位开发的应用
add a few of your apps to this
也能出现在我们的
list as well.
客户名单中
Let's take a look at our
我们再来看一下
framework overview.
我们这套框架的概览
So, all of the classes in PDFKit
PDFKit 里所有的分类
can be put into one of three
全部可以分为
categories.
三个类别
These are our View, Document,
分别是 View  Document
and Support categories, and each
和 Support
of these have their own list of
每一种类别都有
classes as well.
自己的一组类
So, we have our View, which has
比如说 View
a PDFView and PDFThumbnailView.
就有 PDFView 和 PDFThumbnailView
Since we're cross platform, this
鉴于我们支持不同的平台
means on Mac OS, it's going to
这意味着在 Mac OS 上
be an NSView, and on iOS, a
会变成 NSView  在 iOS 上
UIView.
会变成 UIView
For Document, we have
对于 Document 包含的类有
PDFDocument, Page, and
PDFDocument PDFPage
Annotation, which we'll go into
和PDFAnnotation 我们会在
further later.
稍后具体讲解
But we also have our Support
我们还有一组
classes.
归在 Support 下的类
These are things like
其中包括
PDFSelection to PDFTextSelection
PDFSelection 用于完成我刚才提到的
I mentioned, PDFOutline to
PDF 文本选取 PDFOutline 用于
create a table of contents,
创建内容的目录
PDFAction to jump to a URL, and
PDFAction 用于URL跳转
a few more.
还有其他的一些
But when it comes down to it,
不过实际应用时
there are really just four core
其实只要其中4种
classes that do the majority of
核心类别就能做到
what you might want to do with a
你想要的大部分功能
PDF, and these are PDFView,
那就是 PDFView
PDFDocument, Page, and
PDFDocument  PDFPage
Annotation.
还有 PDFAnnotation
But to simplify it even more, to
不过为了进一步简化
create a bare bones application
要创建一个基础框架的应用
to display PDF and interact with
来显示 PDF 和支持交互
it, all you really need to know
真正需要你熟悉的
about is PDFView, and Jeremy's
只有 PDFView
going to show you how to do
下面 Jeremy 会为大家
that.
讲解它的用法
[ Audience Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Awesome!
&gt;&gt; 讲得很棒
Thank you very much, Nicki.
非常感谢 Nicki
All right.
好
So, we really want to emphasize,
所以我们想要强调
you get the power of PDF really
通过对 PDFKit 的很多
straightforward with a lot of
简单运用你能轻而易举地
simple easy use of PDFKit.
发挥出 PDF 的强大力量
What that means is got the demo
也就是说
application.
我这里有个演示应用
It's a desktop application.
是一个桌面程序
It's really straightforward.
它的代码十分简单
It's got a View Controller and a
就是一个 View Controller
View; nothing else.
和一个 View 就这两个
And in the View Controller
在 View Controller 的
source code, and we could
源码中我们
review.
可以看到
There's only three bits of code
这里只有三段代码
that we care about.
需要我们注意
The first is we instantiate a
第一段是用父 bounds 为
PDFView with the parent bounds,
PDFView 创建一个实例
and we know that it's filling
我们知道这会填满
that window in Startup.
Startup 中的相应窗口
We then use Auto Resize to make
然后使用 autoresizingMask
sure that that view always fills
确保显示画面始终会
that window, so even if we
填满窗口这样在我们
resize the window, it'll always
调整窗口大小时显示画面
be fitted.
也会一直跟着变化
And finally, the only actual
最后才是一段真正的
true bit of PDFKit code is we
PDFKit 代码
allow Dragging.
就是 allowDragging  (允许拖动)
What that means is if I launch
也就是说
the application, I can drag and
当我打开这个程序时
drop a PDF file that I have, in
我可以拖动放下我的 PDF 文件
this case from Desktop, and it's
比如现在就是在桌面上操作
a fully interactive view that
整个过程完全支持交互
has all of the same look, feel,
外观感觉性能
and features as Preview, Safari,
都和 Preview Safari 一样
and all of these other first
也和其他所有的
party applications.
第一方应用一样
And what I mean by that is
这里我要说的是
there's text selection for free.
它免费支持文本选取
There's the viewer, of course.
它有查看器不用多说
If we go to the Table of
如果拉到目录这里
Contents, it's fully
我们可以看到
interactive.
它全面支持交互
I could click and jump
我可以点击一下
somewhere.
就直接跳转
I could also right-click and
我也可以右击
maybe change my display layout,
然后可以改变排列格式
change a lot of other options.
也可以改变许多其他选项
I could copy and search text.
我可以复制文本搜索文本
What's really cool about this is
最厉害的是
all of these features are also
所有这些特性
available to you as a developer
你们这些开发者全都能用
where you could programmatically
大家可以通过编程
drive these kinds of changes.
驾驭这些改进
All right.
好
So, I've introduced PDFView kind
我前面对 PDFView 的介绍
of casually, but let me give you
比较笼统  现在让我
some more details.
再多讲些细节
It's this fully customizable but
PDFViewer 全面支持自定义
easy to use PDFViewer.
但又简单易用
And when I say fully
而且我所说的
customizable, what I mean is
全面支持自定义是指
this, how you could change the
你可以改动页面布局
layout, direction, page padding;
方向页面内边距
you could also change so many
还可以改动很多其他元素
more like zoom factors and zoom
比如缩放选项和
behavior.
缩放行为
This is also the appropriate
它也很适合进行
place to do view-to-content and
视图到内容
content-to-view coordinate
和内容到视图的
transforms.
坐标转换
What that means is if you use
也就是说当你用手指
your finger on iOS, and you tap
操作 iOS  并且轻点了一下
that PDFView, we actually can
PDFView 时我们其实会
transform that tap and figure
对这下轻点进行转换
out where exactly in the
找出它在文档中和
document and in that page you
在你触击页面中的
are touching.
精确方位
Now, I've mentioned there's a,
我前面还提到
that they're easy to use, so I
它简单易用
want to give you kind of a
那么我给大家
simple straightforward example
看个简单直观的例子
of setting that document to a
看要如何将一个文档
PDFView.
在 PDFView 里进行设定
Here in SWF, we're initializing
在这里我们用一个 URL
a document with a URL, and then
来初始化一个文档
we assign that document to the
然后将这个文档
View itself.
赋给 View
We take care of everything else.
其余的工作由我们代劳
No matter what content is in
无论这个文档的
that document, we will show it
内容是什么我们都会
in PDFView.
用 PDFView 显示出来
So, I mentioned more of these
前面又讲了
display settings.
更多的显示设置
I want to show you a couple of
我想再给大家
the enumerations.
看几个枚举
PDFDisplay mode is really cool
PDFDisplayMode 特别厉害
because you can actually change
你可以改变
that setup of the document in
文档在你的 PDFView
your PDFView.
里面的设置
So, the first denom is single
它的第一个值
page and, of course, you see one
是 singlePage 当然就是
page at a time.
一次只能看一个页面
There's also single page
此外还有
continuous, and what that means
singlePageContinuous 意思是
is it's the series of pages laid
在垂直方向上
out on the vertical column.
连续显示页面
There's also two up modes, so
此外还有 twoUp 模式
you could kind of get this
可以让你做出这种
iBooks look and feel, and
iBooks 的样式和效果
there's, of course, two up
当然也有
continuous; so, a lot of
twoUpContinuous
options.
选择很多
Next up, new to 2017 is going to
接下来我们在 2017 年
be Display Direction.
新推出了 PDFDisplayDirection
So, if you look at the
所以大家在考虑
continuous modes, you don't have
连续显示模式时
to do vertical; you could also
不必拘泥于垂直方向
do horizontal; and of course,
也可以使用水平方向
this is available on both
当然这个特性目前
platforms today.
在两个平台上都有提供
There's also, unique to iOS this
我们今年还专门针对 iOS
year, the View Pagification.
推出了 View Pagification
What that means is we want to
也就是说我们想让大家
give you the same look and feel
在自己的应用中也能呈现
as iBooks in your application;
iBooks 的外观和效果
so, you could do so by turning
要做到这一点
on that feature.
只要开启这个特性就好
So, here, you could put your
所以你可以将手指
finger on the device, you could
放在设备上左右滑动
swipe, and it will go ahead and
它会即时响应
change between pages for you.
为你切换不同页面
And what's cool is on this
最厉害的地方
bottom.
在下面的底栏
Take a closer look.
我们拉近看一下
We've got PDFThumbnailView, so
通过 PDFThumbnailView
Feature Rich Scrubber for the
我们可为文档本身
document itself.
提供 Rich Scrubber 功能
As you move your finger across
当你在这条板刷上
that scrubber, it'll activate
移动手指时它会激活
the appropriate page that your
你手指触到的各个页面
finger is on, and it'll update
然后在 PDFView 中
PDFView with that active page.
更新相应的活动页面
But of course, if you drive that
当然如果你用 PDFView
page change with PDFView, it'll
处理这项页面变化
go ahead and update
它也会予以执行
ThumbnailView as well.
对 ThumbnailView 进行更新
ThumbnailView isn't limited just
ThumbnailView 并不
to the horizontal access.
仅限于水平显示
Of course, you can set it to the
你也可以
vertical axis.
将它设置成垂直显示
So, we've talked a lot about
那么我们说了很多
PDFView, but let's talk about
PDFView 的特性  现在再来
the core data structures
聊一下核心数据结构
themselves, the Document, Page,
文档页面
and Annotations Model.
和注解模型
So, PDFDocument really is a
PDFDocument 其实
document; no surprise.
就是一个文档没有别的
And the document is going to be
而文档就是
a collection of PDFPages, and
多个 PDFPage 的组合
PDFPages are pretty cool because
PDFPage 非常厉害
they actually own that content
就是它保存着
from your file.
你文件里的所有内容
What you see on screen is owned
你在屏幕上看到的
by PDFPage.
全都保存在 PDFPage 中
The PDFPage does so much more
PDFPage的功能十分丰富
because it's also an owner of
因为它也保存着
all the annotations that you see
你能在屏幕上看到的
on screen.
所有注解
So, Document has pages, Pages
所以文档由页面组成
has content and annotations, and
页面包含内容和注解
to actually create a document,
而要实际创建一个文档
you could either initialize it
你可以让它自行初始化
by itself, and author one from
然后你自己从头写起
scratch, or you could initialize
也可以用一个 URL
it with a URL.
对它进行初始化
But once you have that document,
但在你生成一个文档后
you could modify the collection
你就可以修改
of pages.
它所包含的页面
You could add, swap, insert, and
可以追加交换插入
remove pages.
移除页面
PDFDocument is also really
PDFDocument 也很强大
powerful because this is where
因为它能让你
you could decrypt the document
解密文档
and also save it with
还能用加密方式
encryption.
保存文档
So, we give you that full
我们为你开放了
feature of encryption both on
打开和保存的
opening and saving.
全面加密功能
It also gives you access to
还能让你查看
check what permissions you have
自己对文档
on the document.
都有哪些权限
So, as you unlock it, it's
你在解锁后
really important that you check
一定要注意检查
what could you actually do with
你都可以对文档
that document.
进行哪些操作
This is also where you could get
你也可以通过它
the attributes of a document, so
获取文档的属性
you could figure out who
你可以得知
authored it, when it was
它的创建者是谁
authored, what tools did they
在什么时候创建的
use to author it.
是用什么工具创建的
And finally, a really nice
最后有个很棒的功能
feature, if you want to ever
如果你想在任何时候
search the document, and the
搜索文档
document strings, you could do
或者一系列的文档
so.
完全没问题
PDFDocument has a series of APIs
PDFDocument 包含一系列的 API
to do exactly that.
专门实现这项功能
Let me give you a full, an
我来给大家看个
example, something you kind of
完整的例子在前面
saw earlier, which is we're
其实也看到过
going to set a Document on a
就是在一个视图里
view, but I wanted to show you
设定一个文档但我想让
the explicit path of, we're
大家看到清晰的路径
going to initialize the document
我们要检查你的 Bundle
by checking your bundle.
从而完成文档的初始化
Does it have the PDF file in
这里有没有
question?
我们要的 PDF 文件呢
If it does, then go ahead and
如果有就继续执行
try to initialize that PDF
试着将 PDF 文档初始化
document, and on success, just
初始化成功后
assign it to the View.
就将它赋给 View
We take care of everything else
其余的工作
for you.
由我们替你搞定
A couple of more examples, if
再举几个例子
you want to save the file, it's
如果想要保存文件
really straightforward.
整段代码也是直截了当
Just do write method call with
只要记得在调用方法时
that new file path.
使用新的文件路径
Let's say you want to save width
比如说你想要使用
encryption; it's really
加密宽度  保存这段代码
straightforward too.
也非常直接
Do a writeto with options, and
用一个附带选项的 write(to:)
then the options is the
这个选项是个字典
dictionary where we map special
我们会通过它
enumerations in the header file
在头文件里将特设的
with a password that you care
枚举变量与你设定的
about.
密码进行匹配
So, here, I'm saving the
在这里我用完全的
document with full honor
所有者权限保存文档
permissions, and you could only
你只有使用我的密码
open it using my password Apple.
“Apple” 才能打开它
A couple of more examples, if
再举几个例子
you want to retrieve a page, we
如果你想要检索一个页面
use a base 0 index system.
我们用的是一种基数0索引系统
What that means is the first
也就是说第一个页面
page is an index 0; second page
对应的索引键是0 第二个页面
is an index 1, etcetera.
对应的索引键是1 依此类推
So, retrieving the first page is
因此要检索第一个页面很简单
as simple as doing .page at and
只要使用 .page(at:)
give us that index.
并且提供索引键
The second one is if you want to
第二个例子是如果你想
insert a page, you could do so
插入一个页面可以用
with a page and an index.
insert(at:) 加索引来实现
If you want to exchange pages,
如果你想要交换页面
just give us two indices.
只要提供两个索引键
Finally, if you want to remove a
最后如果你想要
page, again, just pass us an
移除页面也是同样
index.
告诉我们索引键就好
We will take care of the full
当你对文档做了改动
document construction when you
并将它保存到外部磁盘
mutate it and save it out to
我们也会负责搞定
disc.
完整文档的构建
Now, I've mentioned encryption
我前面讲到了
when you save, but let me show
加密保存但让我
you an [inaudible] example when
给大家看个完美的例子
you open the file.
关于打开文件的
So, here, I'm initializing a PDF
这里是我在用给定的 URL
document from a given URL, and
初始化一个 PDF 文档
the very first thing I need to
我要做的第一件事
do is I need to check, is this
就是检查文档
document actually encrypted?
是否使用了加密
If it is, no problem.
如果是没关系
I'm going to try to decrypt it.
我会尝试把它解密
I'm going to decrypt it by using
我在使用 unlockwithPassword
the method unlockwithPassword.
这个方法来解密
And unsuccess.
没有成功
That's great.
这很好
I just need to do one more
我还要再做一件事
thing, which is I need to
就是要检查
actually check what my role and
我的身份
my permissions are.
和我的权限
What I mean by role is that the
我说的身份是指
PDF document file format has
PDF 文档这个文件格式
this really cool idea that you
有个很厉害的思路
could unlock a document with
就是你其实可以用
actually two passwords, right.
两个密码来解锁文档
You've got your owner password,
你可以有个所有者密码
which has full permissions over
对文档拥有
the document.
完全的权限
You could copy, paste, share it,
你可以复制粘贴分享
print it out, or you could have
打印出来也可能
a limited role, like maybe the
你只有有限权限
user role.
比如可能是用户身份
And with this limited role, you
这个有限身份
might have variable permissions.
可能会给你不同的权限
Maybe you can copy, maybe you
也许可以让你复制
can print, but it's not
也许可以让你打印
guaranteed, and as app
具体情况不一定
developers, it's critical that
对于应用开发者来说
when you do unlock a document,
在解锁文档时检查权限
check these privileges.
是至关重要的一步
The reason why is PDFKit will
因为 PDFKit
enforce these privileges for
会对你强制执行
you.
这些权限
So, if you open a document, and
所以如果你打开了一个文档
you can't copy it, right, it's
但是却不能复制
really a bad user experience not
这种用户体验实在很糟
to understand why you can't copy
你会十分困惑为什么
it.
你无法复制它
So, you could check this and
所以你可以先行检查
maybe communicate to the user,
然后也许通知用户一下
hey, this document is unlocked,
嗨  这个文档已经解锁
but with the user password.
但用的是用户密码
That means you don't have full
所以你没有完全权限
permission, and if you do want
如果你愿意提供
to give us the older password,
所有者密码
we could try to unlock it again,
我们可以试着再解锁一次
and you'll be able to copy it
这样一来
after all.
你就能复制它了
So, when you unlock the
当你解锁文档后
document, it returns a Boolean,
系统会返回一个布尔值
but some of these events on a
但是在文档和其他类
document and other classes will
执行上述操作时也有一些
post notifications and will call
会发出提示然后调用
optional delegates.
可选用的授权
A couple of examples is, again,
还是来举几个例子
when you unlock a document,
当你解锁一个文档时
we'll post the document did
我们会显示一条
unlock notification.
文档已解锁的提示
This could have been driven by
这个动作可由
the user because we have a
用户触发因为我们有
default password unlock a view.
默认密码来解锁视图
But also, if you start saving
但同样在你保存文档时
the document, maybe you want to
也许你希望代码中
catch that in some other
能有其他监测模块
observers in code.
探知到你的动作
You could do so with the
提示就可以帮你
notifications.
做到这一点
You could also implement any of
你还可以执行可选的
these delegates, and they
任何一种授权  它们通常
typically match one-to-one.
都有固定的权限匹配
They have very similar function
它们的函数调用
calls.
也差不多是一样的
All right.
好
So, we talked a lot about pages,
那么我们聊了很多页面
or excuse me, a lot about
哦  抱歉是聊了很多
document; let's talk about
文档的部分现在我们再来
Pages.
聊聊页面
So, pages can be retrieved from
页面可从文档中
a document, or they can be
获取也可初始化为
initialized empty; maybe you're
空白页  也许你
offering a new document, or they
提供的是个新文档
could even be initialized with
也可能是用一张图像
an image.
初始化之后的结果
That's a really helpful feature
这是个很有用的功能
if you're trying to translate a
如果你想要把一组图像
collection of images into a PDF
转换为一个 PDF
document.
文档的话
I'll show you an example later.
等下我会给大家看个例子
But also, what's powerful about
此外  PDFPage 的
PDFPages is that it's that
强大之处还在于它也是
Annotations container.
Annotations 的容器
So, if you interact with
当你与 Annotations
Annotations, or if you want to
交互或者想要
mutate Annotations, PDFPage is
修改 Annotations 时就要在
where to do that.
PDFPage 中执行
Finally, PDFPage has a lot of
最后 PDFPage 还有很多的
custom graphics, so if you want
自定义图形如果你想要
to change its size, its
修改页面的尺寸
orientation, or if you want to
方向或者想要
do custom graphics in that
在内容中绘制
content, you could do so with
自定义图形只要使用
the PDFPage class.
PDFPage 就能实现
It also has a series of a really
它也在 API 中提供非常
powerful text selection at API.
强大的文本选取功能
I'll give you an example.
我来给大家看个例子
So, first and foremost, let's
首先让我们用一张图像
create a PDFPage with an image.
创建一个 PDFPage
So, I'm going to use UIImage to
我会使用 UIImage 来实现
go ahead and initialize an image
并且初始化一张图像
asset, and now I'm going to
接着我再来
instantiate PDFPage with an
用一张图像生成
image.
一个 PDFPage 实例
What's really cool about this is
这里厉害的地方在于
if the image has special
如果图像含有
content, like it's a P3 wide
特殊内容比如使用了
gamic color space, we will
P3 广色域我们就会
author that page, and eventually
用 P3 色域创建
the document, with that P3 color
它的页面以及
space.
整个文档
What's also nice is we default
还有一个独到之处就是
the PDFPage to US letter, but
PDFPage 的默认尺寸是 US letter
you could set that size to
但你可以随意重设
whatever you want, but if you
这个尺寸但在你
initialize it with an image,
用图像来初始化它时
we'll always try to maintain
我们会始终尽力
that image's aspect ratio in the
在文档中保留
size in the document.
图像的原始比例
If you want to extract string
如果你想要从一个 PDFPage 中
content from a PDFPage, you
提取一个字符串内容
could do so by just calling the
只需要调用 string 方法
string method.
就能做到
But if you want to get rich text
但如果你想要从文档中
out of that document, you could
获取大量文本则可以
do so with the Attributed
使用 attributedString
string, and this has been
自从我们对可访问性
really, really powerful with our
做了改进后
improvements in accessibility.
它现在的功能非常强大
There's also, like I mentioned
此外我前面也提到过
before, these really powerful
还有这些非常强大的
text selection APIs.
文本提取 API
I'll give you two examples.
我给大家看两个例子
The first one is let's say you
第一个是假设你想要
want to select text at a
选取特定字符
specific character range.
范围内的文本
You could do so by a method on
您可通过 PDFPage 的
the PDFPage called Selection for
一个方法来实现叫做
Range.
Selection(for:[range])
So, here, we'll select character
在这里我们会选取
10 and for a span of 5
第 10 个字符总共
characters.
选取 5 个字符
We'll extract that, and you
我们会提取出这个字符串
could do a lot of geometry
你可以使用 PDFSelection
conversions with the PDF
进行多种几何转换
selection class to figure out
从而找出它在
where visually that is on Page.
页面上的视觉位置
But there's also the means of
但我们也有办法
pulling out text based on
基于几何形状
geometry.
提取文本
So, if you give us a rectangle
因此如果你提供的是
rather than just a span of text,
一个长方形而非一段文本
we could pull out that PDF
我们也可以提取出
selection for you, and there's a
相应的 PDF 选取文本
lot you could do with that.
你可以对它进行多种操作
But I want to go back to
不过我想再说回
Attributed string.
attributedString
I wrote a really simple desktop
我写了一个非常简单的
application where on the left,
桌面应用在左侧
just like in our previous demo,
就跟前面的演示一样
we have a drag and drop PDFView,
是支持拖放的 PDFView
and on the right, we've got a
在右侧是一个
Rich Text field.
富文本视图
And here, I'm going to drag and
在这里我要拖动和
drop a little user manual, and
放下一小张用户手册
then on the left, I'm pulling
然后在左侧我要
out and publishing the
提取和打印出
Attributed string.
attributedString
And this is what's really cool
这里的厉害之处在于
is we maintain the full content
我们能尽最大可能
as best as possible for text
保留完整内容的
positioning, text order, fonts,
文本定位文本顺序字体
color, bolds, and all of these
颜色粗体或细体以及其他的
other attributes.
属性
And it's critically important
这一点格外重要
because this gets exposed to the
因为这一切都会
accessibility system, which is
显示给可访问性系统
available on both Mac OS and
Mac OS 和 iOS
iOS.
都支持这套系统
That means just by adopting
也就是说只要使用
PDFView, you get all of these
PDFView 你便可免费获得
accessibility improvements for
上述的所有可访问性改进
free on both platforms.
而且两个平台均可支持
All right.
好
So, there's another cool feature
那么我们在 2017 年
new to 2017, which is PDFPages
还新增了一个功能
Method Thumbnail of size for a
就是指定显示框尺寸的
display box.
PDFPage 方法 Thumbnail(of:[size])
Oftentimes, you might be in a
很多时候你可能会发现
situation where you have a PDF
你有一个 PDF 文档
document and all you want to do,
而你想做的
nothing more complicated, all
并不复杂
you want to do is just show a
你只是想要显示
preview of a page.
一个页面预览
With this new method, we do all
凭借这个新方法
of that work for you and, again,
我们可以代你搞定这一切
we'll respect the P3 color
同样我们也支持
space.
P3 色域
So, if your document has any
因此如果您的文档中
sort of complicated asset that
有任何一种复杂元素
has a wide gamut color, we'll
采用了广色域
make sure that the UI image or
我们会确保 UI 图像或
the NS image like gets authored
NS 图像这类元素同样
from this is P3 compliance.
使用 P3 色域生成
What's also nice, this will
另一个厉害的地方是
track size to fit the document
它会追踪给定边界内
in the given bounds while
文档的合适尺寸
maintaining aspect ratio.
同时保留原始比例
But that last argument display
不过最后这个参数显示框
box, what is that?
是做什么用的呢
So, to explain that enumeration,
要解释清楚这个枚举变量
I have to kind of explain how
我就要简单解释一下
PDF content works in terms of
PDF 内容为图像时的
graphics.
工作原理
So, we're going to start with
那么我们先从
the Cartesian Coordinate Space.
笛卡尔坐标空间开始
This is the content coordinate
这是内容的坐标空间
space that all PDFPages draw
所有的 PDFPage
into.
都是在这个空间里绘制
So, you've got origin at 00.
所以我们的原点是 00
X positive grows to the right.
X 的正半轴向右延伸
Y positive grows up, and I'm
Y 的正半轴向上延伸
going to put a little string,
我现在输入一小段字符串
I'm going to say "Hello, San
我会输入
Jose."
你好圣何塞
And with this string, I want to
我要把这个字符串
put it on a page, so it's got a
放到一个页面上
location.
所以它会有个位置
I'm going to put that on the
我要把它放到页面上
page, and the page itself, of
而页面本身
course, has a size.
当然也有个尺寸
So, we've got all of these
于是我们现在有了
geometric properties, but
所有的几何特性
something really bothers me, and
但是我遇到了一个问题
what bothers me is it's not
问题就是
centered.
它没有居中
Right? So, we could redraw this
对吧我们可以重新绘制
entire content, but that's
整个内容
really unacceptable and
但这不是好主意
expensive.
成本也很高
No one wants to re-author a PDF
没人想要重新发出和
document by re-issuing and
重新绘制以上所有的
redrawing all of these draw
绘制命令来
commands.
重新生成一个 PDF 文档
So, instead, we're going to take
所以我们要利用
advantage of the power of PDF
PDF 的强大功能
and take advantage of the
利用我之前提到的
enumeration I was talking about.
枚举变量
We're going to take this
我们还是使用这个 PDFPage
PDFPage, and we're going to set
然后为本来的
the frame for that specific
那个显示框设定框架
display box to be slightly
让它轻微
offset.
偏移
It's offset because we want to
之所以要偏移是因为
keep San Jose dead center.
我们要让圣何塞居中
And I don't really like
我也不太喜欢
Landscapes; I want to turn it
横向页面我想把它
into Portrait, and I could do so
转成垂直的同样
again without reissuing any of
我不用重新发出任何
my draw commands, I could just
绘制命令就能做到这一点
set that frame property.
我只要设定一下框架特性
Now, why is it that I could
那么为什么我可以
change to use PDFPage Geometric
不改变内容
Properties without changing the
就变为使用 PDFPage 的
content?
几何特性呢
What's the real benefit other
除了在保存文件时
than we're just saving some time
可以节省些时间外
when saving the file?
这么做还有什么好处呢
The real benefit is PDF comes
真正的好处是 PDF
from the physical printing
在现实世界里
world.
是需要印刷的
That means that there are cases
这意味着有时候
where you actually want to have
你其实想要为
multiple PDFPages for the same
同样的内容生成
content.
多个 PDFPage
You should think about PDFPages
至少在涉及这样的
at least when it comes to this
内容时你应该考虑
content.
使用 PDFPage
When you're drawing it out, you
完成绘制后
should see them as View portals
你应该将它看成是
into your content.
内容的视图入口
There's one box of content, but
内容的边框只有一个
then there could be several view
但是在内容里
portals or pages into that
可以有若干个
content.
视图入口或页面
And the reason why we do that
至于我们这么做的原因
is, take a look at the corners,
大家看一下它的四角
right.
对吧
In the physical printing world,
在纸质印刷环境中
when you're trying to print this
如果你想要用专业的方式
professionally, oftentimes,
进行印刷通常情况下
they're going to print this
都会经过数次印刷
through several passes, and each
每一次印刷
pass is going to lay on a
都会另外叠加
separate layer of ink.
一层油墨
And to do that perfectly, there
而这个过程要做到完美
needs to be some sort of
就需要某种
alignment.
校准方法
So, here, we've authored the
现在我们利用四角处的
page with optical alignment
光学校准字符
characters at each corner so the
创建了这个页面
physical process can put that
这样在印刷过程中
ink perfectly.
就可以完美铺墨了
And that's why we have these
这也是我们会设置
enumerations.
这些枚举值的原因所在
In this case, I'm showing the
现在我给大家看的
digital version, which is the
是电子版对应的枚举值是
Prop Box.
cropBox
That's what PDFKit defaults to,
这是 PDFKit 的默认赋值
and then we're also showing the
我们也放出了
physical version, which is what
纸质版也就是我们
we'll physically print, via the
将会做成印刷品的版本
media box.
对应的枚举值是 mediaBox
There's three more that you
此外还有三个赋值
could play with, and then also
可供大家运用
don't forget what's really
也不要忘记这个功能的
powerful about this is any
真正厉害之处在于
modifications you make to one
你对一个边框所做的任何修改
box, because you're modifying
由于你实际修改的是内容
that content, is going to appear
都会同时显示在
in both Pages.
这两个页面上
All right.
好
So, let's now talk about Custom
现在让我们来说一下
PDFPage Drawing.
自定义 PDFPage 绘制
We've talked about changing
我们聊了很多如何改变
everything else, but what about
各种设置的话题  但绘制内容的
actually drawing content?
实际情况又是怎样的呢
There are three simple steps.
这个过程分为简单的三步
The first is given a PDF
第一步就是  针对
document; we're going to set a
一个 PDF 文档我们要设定一个
PDFDocument delegate.
PDFDocument 的 delegate (权限)
The reason why we set that
而这么做的原因
delegate is Step 2, that
就是第二步
delegate should implement
这个 delegate 应该用
classForPage.
classForPage 来实现
We're going to return a subclass
我们要返回一个
that we've implemented that's
我们已经实现的子类
going to define how do we want
用来定义我们想要的
to draw this PDFPage.
PDFPage 绘制方法
So, in this case, I'm going to
在这个例子中我将说
say please draw with my custom
请使用我的自定义子类
subclass called WatermarkPage.
WatermarkPage 来绘制
Third step, third and final, is
第三步也是最后一步
we need to actually override
我们需要完全重写
that PDFPage subclass' draw
PDFPage 子类的
method.
draw 方法
So, we're going to do draw with
所以我们要使用的绘制方法
box to context.
是内容边框
Let me show you a full example
我会在讲座的最后
and end.
给大家看一个完整的例子
Perfect.
非常棒
All right.
好的
So, here I've got iOS simulator
现在我有一个 iOS 模拟器
running a sample application
运行着一个示例应用
that implements my three rules,
是我三个设定的实施体现
and in this application, I just
在这个应用里我只能
get to scroll around just like a
在各个方向上拉动
normal PDFView, but I want
就跟正常的 PDFView 一样
something different in this
但是我想用这个应用
application.
做些不一样的事情
I want to say that we're
我想对它说
handling really sensitive
我们在处理非常敏感的
documents, and every time one of
文档每当我的某个用户
my users opens these documents,
打开这些文档时
we have to track them.
我们必须追踪他们
We have to know that user X has
我们必须知道用户X
seen this content, and if user X
看过了这个内容他会不会
leaks this content, right, we'll
泄露出去
know exactly who did it.
我们就会知道是谁泄露的
So, our goal is to draw some
那我们的目的就是
custom identifier atop every
在每个单页的顶部
single page, and we could do so
绘制某个自定义标识符
with those three steps.
就可以通过上面那三个步骤来实现
So, the very first step, if we
那么第一步
go to our ViewController,
如果我们打开 ViewController
there's a little bit of overhead
在前面会需要几行代码
to set up the PDFView, but
来设置 PDFView
here's the core step.
不过核心的一步在这里
We are setting the delegate to
我们要把 delegate(权限)
ourselves.
设置给自己
the ViewController.
设置给 ViewController
The reason why we do that, Step
而这么做的原因
2, we're going to declare, like
在第二步我们要声明
you saw previously in the sides,
就像前面在侧栏中看到的
we're going to declare that
我们要把 watermarkPage
watermarkPage as this PDFPage
声明为 PDFPage 的子类
subclass, and we want to return
而它的返回结果就是
that as our customDrawer.
我们想要的自定义绘制器
The final step, Step 3, is we're
最后一步也就是第三步
now overriding the Draw
我们这里在重写 draw 函数
Function, draw with Box 2
用 box to context 来绘制
context, and we're putting all
然后将我们所有的
of our custom graphics inside.
自定义图形放进去
So, before coming to stage
在今天上台之前
today, I commented out
我把这些代码改成了注释
everything just to see what it
好让大家看到
would look like before.
它原本是什么样子
And well, let me show you what
现在我给大家看一下
it looks like after.
改写后的样子
So, in the code, I first call
在这段代码里我先是
Draw super, and then I draw my
调用了 super.draw 然后绘制了
custom graphics, and there's a
我自定义的图形
reason why I do that.
我这么做当然是有原因的
So, when I execute the code with
当我执行这段
that modification, all pages
修改后的代码时
have this graphical content
所有页面都会被添加上
added.
这个图形内容
And what's really nice about
这里漂亮的地方在于
this is if I attempt to save the
如果我打算保存文档
document or print it, it's
或者打印文档我刚才加入的
guaranteed to have that custom
自定义图形肯定会
graphics that I've just put in.
出现在文档里
But I wanted to mention again,
但我想重申一下
order is critical because we
这里的顺序非常重要
respect the painter's algorithm.
因为我们尊重绘制器的算法
What that means is whatever you
也就是说无论你先
draw first, if you draw the
绘制的是什么  如果你先
original content, followed by
绘制原始内容然后绘制
drawing your custom content,
你的自定义内容
your custom content will appear
你的自定义内容就会
above.
出现在最上层
If you flip that, if you draw
如果颠倒顺序先绘制
your custom content and then you
你的自定义内容然后再
draw super, right, the original
调用 super.draw 就会是
content will be above.
原始内容在最上层
So, just keep that in mind when
所以在你添加自定义绘制时
you're vieing custom drawing.
一定要记得这一点
All right.
好
So, we have talked a lot about
那么我们已经讲到了 PDFView
PDFView, PDFDocument, PDFPage; I
PDFDocument PDFPage 的很多内容
think it's time we talk about
现在应该再来讲讲
Annotations.
Annotations 了
Nicki.
Nicki
&gt;&gt; All right, perfect.
&gt;&gt; 好的太棒了
[ Audience Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; All right.
&gt;&gt; 好的
Let's talk about my favorite
我们来讲一下我的最爱
thing, Annotations.
Annotations
First off, we keep saying this
首先我们经常提到
word Annotations a lot.
Annotations 这个词
What are these?
什么是 Annotations 呢
Well, these are interactive
Annotations 是一些
graphical elements that we can
可以让我们添加到 PDF 文档中的
add to a PDF document.
交互性图形元素
These are things as simple as a
它可以是线条正方形
line or a square, but there's a
这类简单的东西但也有
handful of other annotations as
很多其他形式的注解
well, like highlight, underline,
比如高亮下划线
circles, links, and even
圆圈链接甚至是
widgets, which are interactive
小程序  都是交互性的
form elements.
表单元素
We mentioned earlier that
我们前面提过
Annotations are owned by
PDFAnnotation 是
PDFPage.
PDFPage 的一个子类
So, whenever you create an
所以每当你创建一个
Annotation, you add or remove it
注解时你都是
to and from a PDFPage.
在对 PDFPage 进行增减
And then, if your page is in a
然后如果你的页面
PDFView, whenever you update
是在 PDFView 里每当你更新
properties on that Annotation,
这段注解的属性时
we will update it for you in
我们也会为你实时
real time in the View.
更新在视图里
What's fairly new to PDFKit is
PDFKit 最新添加的
our universal Annotation
是对 Annotations 的
support.
全局支持
Okay. What is this?
好吧  这是什么
Well, all those annotations that
我前面给大家
I just showed you, those are the
看过的所有 Annotations
ones that PDFKit supports, and
PDFKit 都可以支持
when I say that, I mean, we have
我这句话的意思是
our own native rendering for
我们为这些类型的注解
those annotation types.
定义了我们的原生渲染方式
But that doesn't mean you're
但这并不代表
limited to only creating those
你就只能创建
types of annotations.
这些类型的注解
With our universal support, you
有了我们的全局支持
can create whatever you want
你可以按你的想法任意创建
because, well, the PDF spec
因为 PDF 规范
defines an annotation as just a
对注解的定义只是
dictionary of keys and values.
一本键值对应的字典
So, we've gone ahead and
于是我们就延伸了一下
mimicked that within PDFKit.
在 PDFKit 里也加入了同样的东西
For example, the PDF spec can
比如说 PDF 规范
have extensions to it that
允许为它添加扩展类
defines all sorts of annotations
定义各种各样的新注解
we've never seen before.
哪怕是我们没见过的
Take the GPS Annotation.
比如说 GPSAnnotation
This can have certain
它可以包含某种
properties, coordinates,
属性坐标
latitude, longitude, and with
维度经度
their universal support, we can
有了对它们的全局支持
go ahead and set those values on
我们可以继续将这些值
our dictionary, and then what
设置成我们的字典
you see is what you get.
做到所见即所得
Whatever you set, we'll go ahead
不管你具体设置的是怎么
and author that into the file
我们都会在你写下后加以执行
whenever you write it out.
把它编写到文件里
Even though the PDFKit might be
哪怕 PDFKit 没有
undefined, you'll still be able
明确定义你仍可以
to save it as part of the
把它保存为
PDFDocument.
PDFDocument 的一部分
What's new this year is we've
我们今年的新改进是
added an extension to this
为这个类添加了扩展
class, which is PDFAnnotation
我们把它叫作
utilities.
PDFAnnotationUtilities
This has a handful of category
它包含一组
methods that make it just that
类别方法能让
much easier to be able to set
设置和获取
and get the properties for
各类注解的属性
annotations that we do support
变得更容易
or just properties that are
无论是我们提供支持的注解
common amongst the annotations
还是各类注解的通用属性
in general, like a color or a
比如颜色
border.
或者边框样式
We'll take a look at our
我们再来看一下
annotations again, but let's
我们的注解
just focus in on one, a line
但是把重点放在其中一个上
annotation.
一条直线的注解
We all know that annotations are
我们都知道注解
just a bunch of properties, so
就是一堆属性的组合
whenever I change the
每当我更改这些属性
properties, here all I've done
比如在这里我就是
are change my line ending styles
更改了直线的两端样式
and my border.
和边框样式
We can make a simple line
我们可以让简单的
annotation look different six
直线注解呈现出
ways.
6 种不同的样子
So, let's take a look at how we
那么我们来看一下
actually set those properties.
具体如何设置这些属性
So, a line, it needs a start and
一条直线要有起点
end point, so we'll set that on
还有终点所以我们使用
our dictionary using SetValue
setValue 在字典里
forAnnotationKey with our
设置这两点用 linePoints
linePointsKey.
来设置 forAnnotationKey
We'll set the line ending styles
我们还要设置直线的两端样式
and want a closed arrow on one
想让它一端是箭头的尾部
end and an open arrow on the
一端是箭头的头部
other, and then we'll change the
然后我们还要
color.
更改颜色
We'll change it to red.
把它变成红色
But remember those category
但是记得我刚才
methods I just talked about,
提过的类别方法吗
let's go ahead and use those to
让我们直接用它们
do the same exact thing.
来实现以上的效果
Here we go.
来
We're still setting the start
我们还是要设置
and end point, the line ending
起终点两端样式
styles, and the color.
还有颜色
And when we compare the two,
我们来对比一下两种方式
sure, the category methods might
确实类别方法这边
be a few extra lines of code,
似乎要多写上几行代码
but it's very clear as to what
但是它非常清晰地
we're doing.
表达了我们在做的事情
When we're setting values on the
当我们为字典设值时
dictionary, we're mimicking the
其实是在模仿规范的做法
spec, and the spec can be a
而规范有时会
little confusing.
有点教人费解
To set an array of numbers or
用一个数字数组
array of strings for our line
或者一个字符串数组
points and line ending styles,
定义直线的两端及其样式
that's just, again, confusing.
实在感觉很费解
With the category methods, it's
而使用类别方法
explicit that you're setting the
可以清晰地看到
start point, the end point, the
你在定义起点终点
start and line style, and the
两端和边框样式
color.
以及颜色
Just makes life a little bit
这多少能让事情
easier.
变得简单点
Okay. Let's create an
好我们来创建
Annotation.
一个注解
Our [inaudible] method takes
我们的初始化方法支持
three properties, bounds, type,
三个属性边界 (bound) 类型
and the dictionary properties.
还有字典属性
Only two of these are required;
只需要用到其中的两个
abounds, we need to know where
边界我们需要知道
it's supposed to be in the page,
它在页面中的具体位置
and then a type.
然后是类型
For here, we're going to create
在这里我们要创建
a square annotation.
一个正方形的注解
The properties parameter, we're
这些属性参数我们现在
going to leave no for now, but
先暂时留空
I'll get to that in a second.
等下我再来讲
Okay. Let's set some properties.
好我们来设置几个属性
We'll set the color on it.
我们要为它设置个颜色
We already know how to do that.
我们已经知道该怎么做了
But we'll set the border as
但是我们也要设置边框
well, and I want to touch on
这里我想
this PDFBorder object for just a
简单讲一下
second.
这个 PDFBorder 对象
The annotation dictionary is
注解字典只是
just a dictionary of keys and
一个键值对应的字典
values, but some of its values
但其中的的一些值
can also be dictionaries, and so
也可以做成字典
you don't have to go and pull up
所以大家不必去翻
the spec and figure out how
规范查找自己
you're supposed to construct
应该如何构建
this border dictionary value.
这个边框字典值
We've already created a support
我们已经为大家
class for you, and that's
创建了一个支持类
PDFBorder.
就是 PDFBorder
We'll set the line width, set to
我们要设置直线宽度
our annotation border property,
赋给我们的注解边框属性
and then when we add it to the
接着将它加入到页面中
page, it looks a little
最后写出来
something like this.
大概就是这样
Just have a simple square,
就是一个简单的正方形
bottom left corner of our page,
在我们页面的左下角
and it's red.
并且是红色的
Let's take a look at that
我们再来看一下
properties parameter though.
属性参数
So, what we can do is we can
我们能做的就是
kind of prebake a dictionary to
可以事先为属性
properties.
指定一个字典
We're going to create a line
我们再来创建
annotation again, and we already
一条直线  我们已经
know it takes line points, line
知道这需要直线的两点
ending styles, color, and now
两端样式颜色
border.
现在再加上边框
So, then, when we [inaudible]
所以我们在
our annotation, we will, instead
进行直线注解时
of using nil for our properties
不再用 nil 来设置属性
parameter use our line
而是使用我们的
attributes dictionary.
字典 lineAttributes
So, when we add it to the page,
将它加入页面后
it looks a little something like
出来的效果大概
this.
是这样
It has a line starting at the
这是一条直线始于原点
origin, going up, and to the
向着右上方延伸
right, has a closed arrow on one
一头带一个箭头
end, and the color is red.
颜色是红色
I want to touch on this one
我想简单讲一下
property that annotations has
一个很好用的
which is really powerful.
注解属性
It's Action property.
就是 Action 属性
Just like PDFBorder was a
PDFAction 跟 PDFBorder 一样
wrapper for a dictionary, so is
是个字典的包装
PDFAction, so you can do things
所以你可以实现多种操作
such as jumping to a URL, and
比如跳转至某个 URL
here we create URL, use that to
这里我们创建了一个 URL
create a PDFAction URL object,
用它来创建一个 PDFAction URL 对象
and then set it on our
然后将它赋给
Annotation.
我们的注解
For here, it's going to be a
在这里就是这个
Link Annotation.
LinkAnnotation
But we can also do things such
不过我们还可以做些别的
as jumping to a specific point
比如跳转至文档中
in a document.
某个特定的点
We can do that by creating a
要做到这点可以使用
PDFDestination object with the
页面和一个给定点创建
page and a point, using that to
一个 PDFDestination 对象
create our PDFAction go to
再用它来创建我们的 PDFActionGoto 动作
action, and then, again, set our
然后同样是设为
Action property.
我们的 Action 属性
Okay. Let's talk about widgets.
好我们再来讲一下小部件 (widget)
Widgets are, again, our
小部件同样是我们的
interactive form elements, but
一种交互性表单元素
these are a little confusing how
但是它们的创建方法
to create, so I want to break it
有点令人费解所以我来
down for you guys.
为大家拆分讲解一下
We have very different flavors
我们设计了各种各样的
of widgets.
小部件
These are text widgets, buttons,
有文本小部件按钮小部件
and choice widgets.
还有选项小部件
And so PDFKit knows what type of
好让 PDFKit 知道要将
widget and interactive element
什么类型的小部件和交互元素
to add to your PDFDocument.
添加到你的 PDF 文档中
You need to let us know.
你需要让我们知道
And this is driven by our widget
这要通过我们的 widgetFieldType 属性
field type property to be either
来控制是做一个
a text button or choice.
文本按钮还是选项
Even further, some of our
不仅如此我们有些子类型
subtypes have more flavors.
还能提供更多选择
Like a button, we can have a
比如说按钮它可以是
radio button, a check box, or a
单选按钮复选框或者
push button, and this is driven
推送按钮具体靠我们的
by our widget control type
widgetControlType 属性
property.
来控制
And same with width or choice
对于选项小部件
widgets.
也是一样
We have a list box, which is
这里是一个列表框
like a TableView, or a combo
视图就像一个表格或者
box, which is like a dropdown,
类似于下拉菜单的组合框
and this is driven by our
这可以通过我们的
isListChoice property.
isListChoice 属性来实现
By default, it's going to be a
它的默认类型为
list box, but I want to let you
列表框  但是我想
know that there are two
让大家知道
different types.
还有另外两种类型
Let's go ahead and create a
让我们直接来
widget.
创建一个小部件看看
We're going to create a text
我们要创建一个
So, our subtype is going to be
所以我们的子类型
widget, but then when we start
就是小部件接着在我们
our properties, we know that we
开始设置属性时  我们知道
have to set the widget field
我们得要指定 widgetFieldType
type, and we're going to set it
那我们就将它
to be text.
设为 text
Then, we'll set a few other
然后我们会设定另外的
properties.
几个属性
We have our background color,
我们设定了背景颜色
font, and a string value, and
字体字符串值
then when we add it to a page,
然后将它添加至页面
it'll look a little something
出来的效果大概
like this.
就是这样
We have our text widget about
我们将这个文本小部件
the middle of the page, the blue
放在了页面中央处
background, and our string,
蓝色背景显示的字符串为
WWDC2017.
WWDC2017
And if this was in a View,
如果这一切是在视图里
whenever I tapped on it or
每当我轻点它
clicked on it, it would be fully
或者单击它时
interactive.
它会全面支持交互
Okay. Let's take a look at a
好我们来看一个
real world example using
现实世界中
widgets.
使用小部件的例子
So, I've already gone ahead and
我已经先写了一个
taken a PDF, which is going to
生成了一个 PDF 内容是
be a survey, and I've added some
一份问卷调查并为它
interactive form elements to it.
添加了一些交互表单元素
Let's take a look at what this
我们来看看
looks like.
最后的结果是什么样
So, here it is.
就是这个
I have text fields, which have
有几行文本栏附带
the blue backgrounds, and then
蓝色背景然后是
buttons, which have my gray
按钮使用我指定的
backgrounds, and since we're all
灰色背景鉴于我们都是
widget wizards, we all know that
小部件魔法师我们都知道
our text fields will have widget
我们的文本栏应该设为
field type text; buttons will
widgetFieldType 文本
have widget field type button,
按钮也是 widgetFieldType 按钮
and then even further, our
不仅如此我们的
buttons will have the proper
按钮还会使用适当的
widget control type set.
widgetControlType 集合
So, we have our radio buttons,
所以我们能看到单选按钮
our check boxes, and then a push
复选按钮还有一个推送按钮
button down here, which is
在下面用来
supposed to reset my entire
重置我的整个
form.
表单
There are some things though
不过这个 PDF 上
that aren't really working right
有几处地方
with this PDF.
也不太对
For example, when I go to enter
例如当我准备输入
my date, which is June 9, you
一个日期 6月9日
can see, it doesn't have the
你能看到它并没有
spacing as I would expect.
显示出我想要的间隔样式
And also, I can enter more
并且我可以输入
characters than what the PDF
更多的字符比 PDF 告诉我
says that I should be able to
应该输入的字符数
enter.
要多很多
That's not right.
这是不行的
Also, when I select my radio
此外当我选择单选
buttons, I can select both at
按钮时我也可以同时
the same time.
把两个都选上
That's not really how radio
这并不是单选按钮
buttons are supposed to behave.
应有的动作
And finally, my button at the
最后我放在最下方的
very bottom, when I click it, it
按钮在我单击时
does nothing.
它一点反应也没有
Well, let's go ahead and change
那好让我们接着来
all of that.
修改所有这些问题
Let's go to our date field.
我们先来看日期栏
So, remember the things that
记得出现的问题
were wrong.
是什么
It was the spacing and the
问题是间隔样式
number of characters that we can
和我们可以输入的
enter.
字符个数
Well, we'll start with the easy
那么我们先从简单的
one, and that's the number of
那个开始也就是
characters.
输入字符的个数
This is driven by our maximum
这要通过我们的 maximumLength
length property.
属性来实现
So, we'll set it to 5, 2 for the
我们将它设为 5
month, 1 for the slash and 1 for
月份 2 个字符斜线1个字符
the day.
日子 2 个字符
So, now, the spacing.
接下来是间隔样式
That seems a little hard to do.
这个问题看上去有点难
But actually, with PDFKit, it
但实际上凭借 PDFKit
really isn't.
这一点都不难
All it is is a property that we
只需要我们设定
have to set, which is our
一个属性也就是我们的
hasComb property.
hasComb 属性
So, this property, what it does
这个属性的用途是
is if it's set, it will divide
被设定后会将我们的
our text widget into an equal
文本小部件切割为
number of partitions or combs to
几个部分或者几处间隔
the number that is set on our
数量就等于我们的
maximum length field.
maximumLength 字段的赋值
So, this property only works in
这个属性仅可配合
conjunction with maximum length.
maximumLength 使用
All right.
好
That's one's done.
一个问题搞定
On to our radio buttons.
接着是单选按钮
The issue here is that they
这里的问题是
weren't behaving like radio
它们的动作不像个
buttons.
单选按钮
So, all our widgets, they
我们所有的小部件
already have their own
都已经有了自己的
identifier, and this is driven
标识符具体是用我们的
by our field name property.
fieldname 属性来控制
So, if you want to group widgets
所以如果你想把小部件
together, they need to have the
聚合在一起就需要它们
same field name.
使用相同的字段名
Let's do that.
我们来试试看
We'll have our yes button be
我们将“是”按钮设为
Question 1.
问题1
And then, our no button also be
然后我们的“否”按钮
I'm going to point out that it
这里我要说一下
doesn't matter what these
这里的名称用什么都没关系
strings are; all that matters is
唯一重要的就是
that the two are the same.
让两者使用同一个名称
But if I were to run this code
但当我运行这段代码
and select a radio button, all
并且选中一个单选按钮后
of them would turn on or all of
结果却是所有选项全部激活
them would turn off.
或者全部关闭
That's because we don't know, we
这是因为我们不知道...
don't have a way to
我们没有一个办法来
differentiate the yes button
区分“是”按钮
from the no button.
和“否”按钮
They're each going to have their
它们需要各自设定
own unique kind of sub
只属于自己的
identifier.
子标识符
We can do that by setting the
要实现这一点只需要设置一下
button widget state string
buttonWidgetStateString
property.
属性
Let's do that now.
我们这就来加上去
We'll set our yes button to yes
将我们的“是”按钮设为“是”
and our no button to no.
“否”按钮设为“否”
But again, it doesn't matter
同样具体用什么字符串
what these strings are.
都无所谓
I can have this one be Nicki and
我也可以这个用 “Nicki”
this one be Brower.
这个用 “Brower”
All that matters is that they're
唯一重要的就是
different.
给他们不同的值
So, now, we've grouped them
现在我们已经用 fieldName
together with our field name
属性将它们聚合在一起
property, but we've also set
但我们也用了
them apart with our button
buttonWidgetStateString 属性
widget state string.
来区分它们
Last but not least, we have our
最后一个问题
reset button.
我们的重置按钮
But again, we want to reset our
同样我们希望它能将
entire form back to its original
整个表单恢复到
state.
初始状态
And just like PDFAction URL and
就像 PDFActionURL
PDFAction go to, we have
和 PDFActionGoto 我们也有
PDFActionResetForm.
PDFActionResetForm 可以用
Go ahead and create that now.
我们现在就来创建它
Well, how this action works is
这个动作的运行原理是
it takes an array of strings,
获取一个字符串数组
strings that represent field
这些字符串就是字段名
names like the ones we just set
就像我们为单选按钮
on the radio button, and the
设置的那些那样
default behavior is when this
它的默认行为是
action is performed, it will
在执行这个动作后
reset all of the widgets that
它会重置所有与
are associated with my array of
我给定的字段名字符串数组
string field names.
相关联的小部件
But I don't want to have to go
但是我并不想一个个地
through and figure out the field
为我所有的小部件
names of all my widgets.
指定和区分这些字段名
That just is too much work for
这对我来说
me.
太繁琐了
So, I'm going to kind of change
所以我要用某种方式
the behavior of this action, and
修改这个动作的行为
I'm going to do that by setting
我的做法就是将
our fields included are clear
fieldsIncludedAreClear 属性
property to false.
设为 false
So, with just one line of code,
就这样只用了一行代码
I've kind of done two different
我就实现了两个
things.
不同的目的
I've now changed the behavior to
现在我已经将行为
where when I press -- when I
修改成在我按下...
perform this action, all of the
在我执行这个动作时
widgets not included in my list
不在我列表内的小部件
are going to be cleared, and
会被清空
also, I haven't set any on my
此外我还没有将任何
list.
小部件设置到我的列表
So, now, when I perform this,
所以现在当我执行这段时
every widget in my document will
我文档里的所有小部件
be cleared, which is exactly
都会被清空这正是
what I wanted.
我想要的效果
And then, of course, we have to
当然接下来我们就要
set the action property on our
为我们的按钮设置 action 属性
button, and that's it, just
就这样就只需要
three lines of code.
这三行代码
So, let's rerun this and fill
现在让我们重新运行
out our survey from the very
重新填写一个
beginning with everything
一切功能完备的
working properly.
问卷调查
Here we go; we have our name,
好了我们来输入姓名
which is Nicki Brower; our date,
Nicki Brower 日期
which is June 9.
6 月 9 日
We have the spacing that we
我们看到了想要的
wanted, and I don't know if you
间隔样式我不知道大家
can hear, but I'm pressing a
能否听见但我正在按动按钮
button and I can't enter more
我也无法继续输入
characters than what is desired,
超过规定数量的字符
which is what we wanted.
就像我们想要的那样
Have you been to a music
您以前曾参加过
festival before?
音乐节吗
No. Wait, yes, I have.
“否”等等“是”我去过
Which of the following music
您曾参加过以下
festivals have you attended?
哪个音乐节
I've been to iFestival,
我去过 iFestival
Swiftopia, but not Applepalooza.
Swiftopia 但没去过 Applepalooza
Give one recommendation to
请给出一条针对音乐节的
improve a music festival.
改进建议
All music festivals should be
所有的音乐节都应该
free.
能免费参加
And I want to point out that our
我还想说明一下
text widgets by default are
我们的文本小部件默认
single line, but if you want
为单行  但如何你想让它
them to be multiline and have
变成多行并且附带
this word wrapping that I have
自动换行就像我这个这样
here, all it is, is a simple
所有这些只需要设置一个
category method that you have to
简单的类别方法
set.
就能做到
And so now, with this PDF, I
现在有了这个 PDF
could save it, and it'll have
我可以保存它  它会记下
all the values that I want, and
我想要的所有数据值
I could send it to people, and
我可以将它发送给别人
they can see my values.
他们也能看到我的数据值
Or if I want, I can still go
或者我想要的话还可以
ahead and clear my entire PDF
接着清空我的整个 PDF
with my Obliviate button at the
使用最下方的
very bottom.
“清除”按钮即可
So, I'll press it, and we're
所以我按一下它一切就又
back to the very beginning,
回归到一开始的样子
which is the behavior that we
这也是我们想要
wanted.
看到的行为
So, I showed you with PDFKit, it
那么我给大家看了 PDFKit
really isn't that hard to take a
它的使用方法并不难不管是
simple PDF, add some widgets,
生成简单的 PDF 还是添加小部件
and now you have a fully
现在你有了一个完全
interactive one that you can
支持交互的 PDF 可以
share with whoever you want.
随意分享给任何人
And I don't know about you guys,
我不知道大家有什么想法
but I think that's pretty cool.
我个人是觉得它挺好用的
So, we're going to go ahead, oh!
那么我们继续下一环节
[ Audience Applause ]
[掌声]
So, we're going to go back to
那么接下来交回给
Jeremy, and he's going to talk
Jeremy 他会为大家
about a few best practices.
介绍几种最佳实践
&gt;&gt; Perfect.
&gt;&gt; 真棒
Thank you very much, Nicki.
谢谢你 Nicki
So, this year, Annotations have
所以在今年 Annotations 经过了
greatly improved, and we've also
大幅改进我们也修正了
fixed a lot of issues in PDFKit
PDFKit 中的许多问题
and greatly improved other
还大幅改进了
functionality too.
其他的功能
And with our experience, we
根据我们的经验
really want to give you a couple
我们很想为大家
of recommendations that you
提供几条建议
could take away and improve on
供大家借鉴用来优化
your code today.
你们的代码
So, a couple of recommendations
那么几条建议
straight away.
直接入正题
Use annotations for any sort of
对于你想在运行时生成的
interactive elements or complex
任何一种交互元素
graphics that you want to do at
或复杂图形
run time.
全部使用 annotation
We've greatly put effort into
我们投入了很大心力
optimizing these graphics, so
来优化这些图形
it's a great option to take
所以非常推荐大家
advantage of.
善加利用
And of course, if you are going
当然如果你想要
to be mutating PDFAnnotations,
修改 PDFAnnotation
take advantage of that
不妨善加利用
PDFAnnotationUtilities category
PDFAnnotationUtilities 类别的
class extension.
类扩展
The reason why, as Nicki said,
其中的原因就如 Nicki 所说
is that these are statically
是因为这些都属于
typed functions.
静态类型函数
You don't have to worry that a
你不用再担心
line point is an array of
一个直线点其实是
points.
一个由多个点组成的数组
Actually, a line point is just a
实际上一个直线点
CG point, a pair of CG points.
就是一个 CG 点一对 CG 点
It's really straightforward.
这个概念非常清晰
Finally, if you want to do a
最后如果你想要完成
custom PDFPage drawing, it is
自定义 PDFPage 绘制
required that your code be
就需要让你的代码
thread-safe.
做到线程安全
The reason why is, again, we've
这同样是因为
put so much effort into
我们投入了很多心力
optimizing PDFKit to draw as
来优化 PDFKit 让它
fast as possible, we want to
尽可能地快速绘制
take advantage of all the cores
我们希望能够好好利用
that our different platforms
我们的不同平台用到的
have.
所有核心
And since many of our platforms
鉴于我们有许多平台
are multi-core, it's absolutely
采用多核设计完全有可能
possible that two threads might
出现两个线程同时
be drawing your PDFPage maybe in
在主视图中绘制 PDFPage
the main view and PDFPage as a
和在缩略图中绘制 PDFPage
thumbnail at the same time.
的情况
So, make sure that your code is
所以一定要确保
thread-safe.
你的代码线程安全
And along these lines, if you
出于同样原因在你
are doing custom PDFPage
执行自定义 PDFPage 绘制时
drawing, make sure that you call
确保你在恰当的时点
super at the appropriate time.
调用 super
If you want to put your graphics
如果你想让你的图形
on top of the existing content,
覆盖在现有内容的上方
call super, and then execute
先调用 super 然后再执行
your custom drawing code.
你的自定义绘制代码
Or if you want to put your
或者你想把自定义图形
custom graphics behind that
叠压在内容的下方
content, do your custom code
那就先执行你的代码
first, and then execute super
最后再来执行
last.
super
Now, what we don't recommend,
接着我们建议不要
moving forward, is because
在今后应用中做的事
PDFView derives from UIView and
由于 PDFView 在两个平台上
NSView on each platform
分别以 UIView 和 NSView 为基础
respectively, those view classes
这些视图类让你
give you the ability to call a
可以调用一个叫作
method, call set needs display
setNeedsDisplay 的方法
or some mutation of that method.
或者它的一些变种
And that method is really
这个方法的调用成本
expensive because refreshing all
其实非常高  因为这会
of the content at once is just
一次性地刷新所有内容
expensive.
成本是很高的
So, try to avoid it.
所以尽量别用它
Again, if you want to do custom
同样如果你想要
graphics, take a look at
使用自定义图形不妨
Annotations.
考虑 annotation
Finally, don't mutate PDFPage
最后不要同时在
properties at the same time from
不同的线程中修改
different threads.
PDFPage 的属性
A good example is don't rotate
一个很好的例子就是
the PDFPage while you're drawing
不要在旋转 PDFPage 的同时
a thumbnail at the same time.
又去绘制缩略图
There might be some undefined
在这类情况下
visual effects that might happen
可能会出现一些
during those cases.
未定义的视觉效果
And finally, this is specific to
最后专门针对
Mac OS only, but try to stay
Mac OS 平台尽量不要
away from the deprecated drawing
使用已弃用的
methods.
绘制方法
The reason why goes all the way
这里的原因可以一直
back to multi-threaded drawing.
追溯到多线程绘制的问题
So, we build these really
总之我们搭建了这些
complicated contexts so you
非常复杂的上下文
could draw your beautiful
好让大家可以绘制出
graphics into, and we want to
漂亮的图形我们也希望
give you these contexts
能将这些上下文
explicitly.
清晰地传达给你们
That's what the new signatures
这些新命名就是
are for.
出于这样的目的
The old signatures had an
以前的命名方式表达的
implicit context, and we want
上下文很模糊而我们想让
you to avoid that as much as
大家尽量避免
possible.
这种问题
So, these are bits and pieces
以上就是我们给大家的
that we recommend.
几条小建议
But looking at PDFKit again, we
但再说回 PDFKit
want to emphasize it's really
我们想要强调
easy for app developers to get
如今应用开发者对于 PDF 处理
started with PDFHandling today.
真的非常容易上手
They could use PDFView just to
他们可以只是用 PDFView
look at a document, or you could
查看一个文档也可以
totally author a brand new one,
完全创建一个全新的文档
or you could take an existing
又或者使用现有的文档
document, add a bunch of new
为它添加一些
content inside.
新的内容
It's also really easy to read,
要读取修改保存这些文件
modify, and write these files,
也十分容易
and you could write it with the
你还可以用 PDF 规范
latest encryption supported by
支持的最新加密方法
the PDF specification.
来保存文件
Of course, when you do write
当然在你使用最新的
these files with that latest PDF
PDF 规范保存这些文件时
specification, you could author
也可以用这些
these files with these really
非常强大的表单字段小部件
awesome form field widgets.
来创建这些文件
So, that means fully interactive
这意味着将有支持完全交互的
forms that you could fill out
表单供你填写
for your business needs or
满足你的企业需要
whatever other needs you have.
或者你的任何其他需要
Finally, just by adopting
最后通过使用 PDFView
PDFView, don't forget, you get
别忘了还能让你
rich accessibility improvements
获得具备充分可访问性的改进
that we've worked really hard on
这是我们这一年里
this year for both platforms.
在两个平台上的努力成果
So, your users will really take
如果你的用户有任何
advantage of that if they have
可访问性方面的需要就可以
any accessibility needs, and you
方便地利用这项成果
don't have to worry about any
你也不用担心
sort of custom programming.
任何自定义的编写程序
Nicki and I want to thank you
我和 Nicki 想要
very, very much for coming to
真心地感谢各位
today's session.
参加今天的讲坛
If you have any questions at
大家若有任何问题
all, [applause] thank you.
[掌声] 谢谢
Please visit our website, or
请查看我们的网站
come down to the podium.
或者直接来讲台这里
We'll gladly answer any
我们很愿意解答
questions.
任何问题
Have a fantastic rest of WWDC.
祝大家在 WWDC 上玩得开心
Thank you again.
再次感谢